# LOREN PIERCE



pierce\_loren@yahoo.com 503-688-8696 www.lorenpierce.com



## SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

Teamwork
Leadership
Self-Motivation
Communication
Problem Solving
Mentoring

## TECHNOLOGY SKILLS

MS Office
Windows OS
PC Hardware
PC Software
Networking
Programming

#### **EDUCATION**

Monterey, CA 2013 Bachelors of Science in Business Administration

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Completed skills courses in Python, Java, Javascript, HTML, and SQL on SoloLearn Android app.

Published an Android app to the Google Play market.

Completed "Learn Java" and "Beginner Android Development" tracks on teamtreehouse.com.

Created a YouTube Channel for game tutorials. The first video posted received over 2,500 views.

Completed Java and Javascript skills training on Codecademy.com.

## **Profile**

Navy Veteran with degree in Business seeking to move from the finance industry to the technology industry. Technology enthusiast that spent most of the past two years learning programming through self-education while working full time. Has demonstrated aptitude for learning quickly, and has performed software and hardware maintenance and repair on systems ranging from personal computers to missile launchers.

## **Experience**

Portland, OR

3/2013 - 3/2017

## **Loan Documentation Specialist**

US Bank

Accomplishments:

- Managed an average of 1,600 electronic and paper loan files per year.
- Utilized MS Office Suite to perform fast and accurate evaluation of customer exposure in line with department production requirements.
- Prepared loan documents for underwriters with accuracy per detailed policies and procedures for loans up to \$2.5 Million.
- Communicated with field personnel and local leadership to solve problems with loan packages.

Portland, OR 3/2014 - 3/2017

## **Rider Training Instructor**

Team Oregon Motorcycle Safety Program

Accomplishments:

- Instructed riders in safe motorcycle operation to help them earn their endorsement in the state of Oregon.
- Identified rider's learning needs to help them best retain course information.
- Provided individualized coaching to riders.
- Collaborated with instructor team to maintain and improve standards of instruction that are currently rated the highest in the nation.

Portland, OR 5/2012 - 3/2013

# **Temporary Employee – US Bank SBLC File Room**

Randstad Temporary Staffing

Accomplishments:

• Organized two large file rooms containing around 35,000 loans files into one room to greatly improve the ability of existing file room staff to locate files.

Petaluma, CA 6/2011 - 4/2012

#### **Human Resources Assistant**

Cross Check Inc

Accomplishments:

- Programmed and managed formulas in MS Excel for tracking hiring statistics.
- Entered and analyzed applicant resume data in MS Access.
- Tracked, analyzed and presented statistics related to hiring operations.

Salinas, CA 5/2009 - 4/2011

## **Technology Program Assistant**

Boys and Girls Clubs of America

Accomplishments:

- Maintained, upgraded and installed new software and hardware on computers used for educating youth.
- Diagnosed and repaired hardware and software issues.
- Supervised and educated youth in technology skills.

San Diego, CA 5/2001 - 5/2005

# **Gunner's Mate Missile Technician, Second Class**

**United States Navy** 

Accomplishments:

- Performed technical maintenance and repairs on MK41 VLS Missile System resulting in 98.6 percent uptime.
- Part of a high-performance team providing support for crew small arms and mission critical ship weapon systems.
- Reported information relating to maintenance procedures to senior leadership.